# Amlan Banaji

Curriculum Vitae

Email: A.F.Banaji "at" lboro.ac.uk

Website: <u>amlan-</u> <u>banaji.github.io</u>

Nationality: UK

Research Associate in Fractal Geometry at Loughborough University's mathematics department.

# **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

My main research interests relate to the geometry and dimension theory of fractal sets and measures. I have worked with fractals generated by conformal and non-conformal iterated function systems. I am currently interested in Fourier decay of fractal measures, and interpolating between different notions of dimension. I am interested in finding connections between fractal geometry and other areas of mathematics.

## PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS

#### Submitted:

- 8. A. Banaji and I. Kolossváry. *Intermediate dimensions of Bedford–McMullen carpets with applications to Lipschitz equivalence*, <u>arXiv</u>
- 7. A. Banaji, A. Rutar and S. Troscheit. *Interpolating with generalized Assouad dimensions*, arXiv
- 6. A. Banaji and J. M. Fraser. Assouad type dimensions of infinitely generated self-conformal sets, arXiv

#### Accepted:

- 5. A. Banaji. *Generalised intermediate dimensions* To appear in **Monatshefte für Mathematik**. <u>arXiv</u>
- 4. A. Banaji. *Metric spaces where geodesics are never unique* To appear in the **American Mathematical Monthly**. <u>arXiv</u>

### Published:

- 3. A. Banaji and J. M. Fraser. *Intermediate dimensions of infinitely generated attractors* **Transactions of the American Mathematical Society** 376 (2023), 2449–2479. <u>arXiv</u>
- 2. A. Banaji and H. Chen. *Dimensions of popcorn-like pyramid sets* **Journal of Fractal Geometry** 10 (2023), 151–169. <u>arXiv</u>
- 1. A. Banaji and A. Rutar. *Attainable forms of intermediate dimensions* **Annales Fennici Mathematici** 47 (2022), 939–960. <u>arXiv</u>

### **EDUCATION**

**University of St Andrews** 

2019-present

**PhD Mathematics** 

**Topic:** Fractal geometry and dimension theory

With the **Analysis Research Group** 

**Supervisors:** Prof. Jonathan Fraser (primary), Prof. Kenneth Falconer

Fully funded by the **Leverhulme Trust** 

**University of St Andrews** 

2018-2019

**MSc Mathematics, Distinction** 

**GPA**: 19.5/20. Ranked 1<sup>st</sup> in the Faculty of Science and Medicine

Dissertation:

<u>Solvability of Partial Differential Equations on Fractal Domains</u> (Score: 19.1/20, supervised by <u>Professor Kenneth Falconer</u>)

University of Cambridge,

King's College 2015–2018

**BA (Hons) Mathematics** 

**Selected Part II courses:** Linear Analysis, Analysis of Functions, Topics in Analysis, Differential Geometry, Riemann Surfaces, Logic and Set Theory

2013-2015

#### A-Levels:

 $Mathematics(A^*)$ ,  $Further\ Mathematics(A^*)$ ,  $Physics(A^*)$ ,  $Chemistry(A^*)$ , History(A)

# **SELECTED PRIZES**

*2019*: **Postgraduate Gray Prize** for the best MSc student in the Faculty of Science and Medicine at the University of St Andrews.

# **TALKS**

I have given at least 30 talks (see <a href="https://amlan-banaji.github.io/files/BanajiTalks.pdf">https://amlan-banaji.github.io/files/BanajiTalks.pdf</a> ) at conferences and seminar series including:

- Fractal Geometry (celebrating Prof. Kenneth Falconer's 70th birthday, ICMS, Edinburgh, 4/7/23)
- Multifractal analysis and self-similarity (CIRM, Marseille, 30/6/23)
- Diophantine Approximation, Dynamics, and Fractals (Exeter, 22/6/23)
- Thermodynamic Formalism: Non-additive Aspects and Related Topics (Bedlewo, 16/5/23)
- Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems Seminar (Bristol, 13/3/23)
- Analysis Seminar (Edinburgh, 13/3/23)
- One World Fractals (online, 18/1/23)
- Mathematics Research Day (St Andrews, 1/12/22)
- Szenzhen Technology University Mathematics Colloquium (China (online), inaugural talk, 22/10/22)
- Fractals and Related Fields IV (Porquerolles, France, 5/9/22)
- Geometry of Deterministic and Random Fractals (Budapest University of Technology and Economics, 30/6/22)
- <u>Junior Ergodic Theory Meeting</u> (ICMS, Edinburgh (30/3/22) and online (19/3/21))
- Workshop on affine and overlapping iterated function systems (Bristol, 11/5/22)
- Dynamics and Group Geometry Early Researchers Seminar (DAGGER) (Warwick, 30/5/22 and 1/3/21)
- Analysis Seminar (St Andrews, 22/3/23, 3/5/22, 12/10/21, 20/4/21, 30/6/20)

### **EXPERIENCE**

Teaching undergraduate tutorials at the University of St Andrews:

Most recent student feedback score: 1.5 on a scale from 1 to 5 (where 1 is highest).

2019–2022: MT2502 Analysis (10 groups total)

2021: MT2505 Abstract Algebra (2 groups)

2020: MT1003 Pure and Applied Mathematics (2 groups)

- 2018–2022: **Tutoring** mathematics (undergraduate, A level and STEP) with G5 Education, Oxford Exclusif Tutorial Agency, PhD Tutors, Sishu Chinese School, and privately.
- 2018: LMS-funded **Cambridge Summer Research in Mathematics (SRIM) project** on Leray-Schauder Topological Degree Theory and its applications to Partial Differential Equations.

### **SERVICE**

- 2023–present: Co-organiser of the Loughborough University Dynamical Systems Seminar
- 2022–present: **Referee** for *Proc. Roy. Soc. Edinburgh Sect. A* and *Collog. Math.* and *J. Math. Anal. Appl.*
- 2022: **Organiser** of St Andrews Analysis Reading Group
- *2021*: **Co-organiser** of the Postgraduate Interdisciplinary Mathematics Symposium (PIMS), St Andrews.
- 2019–2021: **Treasurer** of St Andrews Mindfulness Society.

# **MEMBERSHIP OF PROFESSIONAL BODIES**

- 2022–present: London Mathematical Society
- 2020–present: Edinburgh Mathematical Society
- 2019–present: Institute of Mathematics and its Applications